Inventory of the Stanley Karnow papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject Files, 1952-1985
  - Thailand: Internal relations, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 60: 4)
  - Thailand: Internal relations, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 60: 5)
  - Thailand: Internal relations, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 60: 6)
  - Thailand: The occult (Box-folder 61: 1)
  - Thailand: Sarit corruption, 1964 January-June (Box-folder 61: 2)
  - Thailand: Sarit corruption, 1964 July-December, undated (Box-folder 61: 3)
  - Turkey (Box-folder 61: 4)
  - United States Congress, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 61: 5)
  - United States Congress, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 61: 6)
  - United States Information Agency (U.S.I.A.), 1968-1972 (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - United States Information Agency (U.S.I.A.), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 62: 2)
  - United States: Involvement in Asia, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - United States: Involvement in Asia, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 62: 4)
  - United States: Relations: India and Pakistan, 1971 January-September (Box-folder 62: 5)
  - United States: Relations: India and Pakistan, 1971 October-December (Box-folder 62: 6)
  - United States: Relations: India and Pakistan, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - United States: Relations: Japan, 1971 September - 1972 May (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - United States: Relations: Japan, 1972 June - 1974 May (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - United States: Relations: Thailand, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - United States: Relations: Thailand, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1973 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1974 January-June (Box-folder 64: 2)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1974 July-December (Box-folder 64: 3)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1975-1978 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1979 (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - United States: Relations: U.S.S.R., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - United States: Relations: Western Europe, 1973 January-September (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - United States: Relations: Western Europe, 1973 October-December (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - United States: Relations: Western Europe, 1974 January-February (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - United States: Relations: Western Europe, 1974 March-December (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - United States: Relations: Western Europe, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - United States: Vice presidency (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - U.S.S.R., 1970-1976 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - U.S.S.R.: Domestic relations (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - U.S.S.R.: Foreign relations (Box-folder 66: 1)
  - U.S.S.R.: Relations with Asia, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 66: 2)
  - U.S.S.R.: Relations with Asia, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - U.S.S.R.: Relations with Asia, 1969 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - U.S.S.R.: Relations with Asia, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - U.S.S.R.: Relations with Japan, 1964 May - 1973 October (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Vietnam (Box-folder 67: 2)
- Asian American Research Materials
  - Chinese Americans
    - Identity (Box-folder 98: 2-4)
    - Immigration (Box-folder 98: 5)
    - Discrimination against (Box-folder 98: 6)
    - Chinese Exclusionary Act (Box-folder 98: 7-10)
    - Chinatown (Box-folder 99: 1)
    - Crime (Box-folder 99: 2)
    - Culture (Box-folder 99: 3)
    - California (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - Education (Box-folder 99: 5)
    - Economy (Box-folder 99: 6)
    - Police, judges, lawyers (Box-folder 99: 7)
    - Social
      - General (Box-folder 99: 8)
      - Drugs (Box-folder 99: 9)
      - Youth (Box-folder 99: 10)
      - Family (Box-folder 99: 11)
      - Health (Box-folder 99: 12)
      - Elderly (Box-folder 99: 13)
      - Women - beauty contests (Box-folder 99: 14)
      - Marriage (Box-folder 99: 15)
      - Dating (Box-folder 99: 16)
    - Politics (Box-folder 100: 1)
    - Woo, Michael (Box-folder 100: 2)
    - Interview, Pauline Chu, candidate for City Council, Queens, 1991 (Box-folder 100: 3)
    - Interview, Art Wong, Washington State House of Representatives, 1991 (Box-folder 100: 4)
    - Interview, Judy Chu, Mayor of Monterey Park (Box-folder 100: 5)
    - Interview, I. M. Pei, 1992 (Box-folder 100: 6)
    - Lin, Maya (Box-folder 100: 7)
    - California (Box-folder 100: 8)
    - New York (Box-folder 100: 9)
    - Medicine (Box-folder 100: 10)
    - News media (Box-folder 100: 11)
    - Sports (Box-folder 100: 12)
    - Technology (Box-folder 100: 13)
    - Industry (Box-folder 100: 14)
    - Racial tension (Box-folder 100: 15)
    - London, Jack (Box-folder 100: 16)
    - Opium trade (Box-folder 100: 17)
    - Politics (Box-folder 100: 18)
    - Origins of China (Box-folder 100: 19)
    - Gompers (Box-folder 100: 20)
    - Dee, Woodworth (Box-folder 100: 21)
    - History
      - Labor (Box-folder 101: 1)
      - Social (Box-folder 101: 2)
      - General (Box-folder 101: 3)
      - Local histories (except California and Hawaii) (Box-folder 101: 4)
      - Chinese Exclusionary Act, legal issues and cases (Box-folder 101: 5-6)
    - Vincent Chin case, Monterey Park, California
      - General (Box-folder 106: 1)
      - Interview, Judy Chu (Box-folder 106: 2)
      - Interview, Lily Chen (Box-folder 106: 3)
      - Interview, Evelyn Diederich (Box-folder 106: 4)
      - Interview, Danny Chang (Box-folder 106: 5)
      - Interview, Tim Fong (Box-folder 106: 6)
  - Japanese Americans
    - General (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - Experiences (includes interviews) (Box-folder 102: 1)
    - Hawaii (Box-folder 102: 2)
    - Identity (Box-folder 102: 3)
    - Immigration (Box-folder 102: 4)
    - Economy (Box-folder 102: 5)
    - Legal (Box-folder 102: 6)
    - Labor (Box-folder 102: 7)
    - Social (Box-folder 102: 8)
    - California (Box-folder 102: 9)
    - Discrimination (Box-folder 102: 10)
    - General (Box-folder 102: 11)
    - Immigration (Box-folder 102: 12)
    - U.S. Western influence on Japan (Box-folder 102: 13)
    - General (Box-folder 103: 1)
    - Culture
      - General (Box-folder 103: 2)
      - Film (Box-folder 103: 3)
      - Theater (Box-folder 103: 4)
      - Television (Box-folder 103: 5)
      - Music (Box-folder 103: 6)
      - Art (Box-folder 103: 7)
      - Sculpture / woodworking (Box-folder 103: 8)
      - Photography (Box-folder 103: 9)
    - Discrimination
      - General (Box-folder 103: 10)
      - Violence (Box-folder 103: 11)
    - Economy
      - General (Box-folder 103: 12)
      - Business (Box-folder 103: 13)
    - Attitudes towards Japan (Box-folder 103: 14)
    - Education
      - General (Box-folder 103: 15)
      - Achievement (Box-folder 103: 16)
      - Teachers (Box-folder 103: 17)
    - Crime (Box-folder 103: 18)
    - Consumer market
      - General (Box-folder 103: 19)
      - Media publication (Box-folder 103: 20)
      - Real estate (Box-folder 103: 21)
    - Sports (Box-folder 103: 22)
    - Science and technology (Box-folder 103: 23)
    - Law (Box-folder 103: 24)
    - Politics (Box-folder 103: 25)
    - Racial tensions (Box-folder 103: 26)
    - San Francisco (Box-folder 103: 27)
    - Social
      - Marriage (Box-folder 103: 28)
      - Family (Box-folder 103: 29)
      - Elderly (Box-folder 103: 30)
      - Women - beauty contests (Box-folder 103: 31)
      - Health (Box-folder 103: 32)
    - Internment
      - Interview, Michio Kaku (Box-folder 104: 1)
      - General (Box-folder 104: 2-6)
      - Legal (Box-folder 104: 7)
      - Redress (Box-folder 104: 8)
      - California Assembly (Box-folder 104: 9)
    - World War II (Box-folder 104: 10)
  - Indian Americas
    - History
      - General (Box-folder 105: 1)
      - Discrimination (violence) (Box-folder 105: 2)
      - Legal (Box-folder 105: 3)
      - Immigration (Box-folder 105: 4)
      - Exclusion (Box-folder 105: 5)
      - American view of (Box-folder 105: 6)
      - Religion (Box-folder 105: 7)
      - Independence movement (Box-folder 105: 8)
      - Television (Box-folder 105: 9)
      - Intellectuals (Box-folder 105: 10)
    - Education (Box-folder 105: 11)
    - Economy
      - Business (Box-folder 105: 12)
      - Real estate (Box-folder 105: 13)
    - Culture (Box-folder 105: 14)
    - Attitude towards India (Box-folder 105: 15)
    - General (Box-folder 105: 16)
    - Discrimination
      - General (Box-folder 105: 17)
      - Violence (Box-folder 105: 18)
    - Technology and science (Box-folder 105: 19)
    - Social
      - Family (Box-folder 105: 20)
      - Marriage (Box-folder 105: 21)
      - Youth (Box-folder 105: 22)
    - Politics (Box-folder 105: 23)
    - Identity (Box-folder 105: 24)
    - Immigration (Box-folder 105: 25)
  - Hawaiian Americans (Box-folder 105: 26)
  - Filipino Americans
    - Experiences and interviews (Box-folder 106: 7)
    - History
      - General (Box-folder 106: 8)
      - Labor (Box-folder 106: 9)
      - Social (Box-folder 106: 10)
      - Immigration (Box-folder 106: 11)
      - Discrimination (Box-folder 106: 12)
    - Education (Box-folder 106: 13)
    - Discrimination (Box-folder 106: 14)
    - Culture (Box-folder 106: 15)
    - Identity (Box-folder 106: 16)
    - Immigration (Box-folder 106: 17)
    - Politics (Box-folder 106: 18)
    - General (Box-folder 106: 19)
    - Attitude towards the Philippines (Box-folder 106: 20)
  - Asian Americans
    - General (Box-folder 107: 1-3)
    - Politics (Box-folder 107: 4-6)
    - Immigration
      - General (Box-folder 108: 1)
      - Identity (Box-folder 108: 2)
      - General (Box-folder 112: 2)
      - U.S. policy (Box-folder 112: 3)
      - Europe (Box-folder 112: 4)
    - White American attitudes towards Asian Americans (Box-folder 108: 3-4)
    - Politics, fundraising
      - Chang, Johnny (Box-folder 109: 1)
      - Gandhi, Yogesh (Box-folder 109: 2)
      - Haley, Maria (Box-folder 109: 3)
      - Huang, John (Box-folder 109: 4)
      - Hsia, Maria (Box-folder 109: 5)
      - Kanchanalak, Pauline (Box-folder 109: 6)
      - Lum, Gene and Nora (Box-folder 109: 7)
      - Riady, James (Box-folder 109: 8)
      - Sioeng, Ted (Box-folder 109: 9)
      - Yan Lin Trie, Charlie (Box-folder 109: 10)
      - Tom, Maeley (Box-folder 109: 11)
      - Summary of findings (Box-folder 110: 1)
      - General (Box-folder 110: 2)
      - Lee, Bill (Box-folder 110: 3)
      - Locke, Gary (Box-folder 110: 4)
      - Fundraising (Box-folder 110: 5-8)
    - History
      - General (Box-folder 111: 1)
      - Exclusion (Box-folder 111: 2)
      - Crime (Box-folder 111: 3)
      - Labor (Box-folder 111: 4)
      - Economic (Box-folder 111: 5)
      - Immigration (Box-folder 111: 6)
      - Discrimination (Box-folder 111: 7)
      - Education (Box-folder 111: 8)
      - Legal (Box-folder 111: 9)
    - New York (Box-folder 111: 10)
    - Economy
      - General (Box-folder 111: 11)
      - Real estate (Box-folder 111: 12)
      - Business (Box-folder 111: 13)
      - Finance (Box-folder 111: 14)
      - Labor (Box-folder 111: 15)
    - Discrimination (Box-folder 111: 16)
    - Ethnicity and race (Box-folder 112: 1)
    - Foreign students in the U.S.
      - General (Box-folder 112: 5)
      - Japanese (Box-folder 112: 6)
      - P.R. China (Box-folder 112 :7)
    - Asian diaspora
      - France (Box-folder 112: 8)
      - Britain (Box-folder 112: 9)
      - Canada (Box-folder 112: 10)
      - Australia (Box-folder 112: 11)
      - Southeast Asia (Box-folder 112: 12)
    - Demography
      - General - population (Box-folder 112: 13)
      - Economic (Box-folder 112: 14)
      - Census issue (Box-folder 112: 15)
    - Culture
    - Affirmative action
    - Education
      - General (Box-folder 113: 1)
      - Achievements and explorations (Box-folder 113: 2)
      - Problems and pressures (Box-folder 113: 3)
      - Teachers - administrators (Box-folder 113: 4)
      - Desegregation - bilingual education (Box-folder 113: 5)
      - Representation (Box-folder 113: 6)
      - Ethnicity (Box-folder 113: 7)
    - Crime
      - General (Box-folder 113: 8)
      - Organized (Box-folder 113: 9)
      - Gangs (Box-folder 113: 10)
    - Law
      - Lawyers (Box-folder 113: 11)
      - Judges (Box-folder 113: 12)
      - Police (Box-folder 113: 13)
- Philippines Research Materials, 1973-1987
  - Correspondence, 1973-1989 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Economy, post Marcos (Box-folder 80: 2)
  - Economy (Box-folder 80: 3)
  - Human rights (Box-folder 80: 4-5)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 80: 6)
  - Marcos (Box-folder 80: 7-8)
  - Interview, Jose Diokno (Box-folder 80: 9)
  - Martial law (Box-folder 80: 10-11)
  - Martial law (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Interviews, Father Eugene Casper and Father Tom O' Brian (Box-folder 81: 2)
  - Human rights (Box-folder 81: 3-8)
  - Letters and speeches, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Reagan administration on the Philippines (Box-folder 82: 2-3)
  - Marcos (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - Interview, Phil Habib, 1986 (Box-folder 82: 5)
  - U.S. State Department telegrams (Box-folder 82: 6)
  - Philippines in turmoil: Implications for U.S. policy (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - Washington D.C. files, 1982-1984
    - Paul Wolfowitz statement, 1984 (Box-folder 82: 8)
    - James A. Kelly statement, 1984 (Box-folder 82: 9)
    - National Security Council, Solarz hearing, 1984 (Box-folder 82: 10)
    - Ferdinand Marcos visit to the U.S., 1982 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - Karnow notes on meeting with Cory Aquino (Box-folder 82: 12-13)
  - Corazon Aquino speeches, 1986 (Box-folder 82: 14)
  - Election, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 83: 1-5)
  - U.S. involvement in elections, 1986 (Box-folder 83: 6)
  - U.S. Congress concerns about Philippine elections, 1986 (Box-folder 83: 7)
  - Interview, William Overholt, 1987 (Box-folder 83: 8)
  - U.S. policy towards Philippines, talk with Leslie Gelb, 1986 (Box-folder 83: 9)
  - U.S. involvement in elections, 1986 (Box-folder 83: 10)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 84: 1-4)
  - Interview, Virginia Licuanan (Box-folder 84: 5)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 84: 6-9)
  - Bibliographies (Box-folder 84: 10)
  - Karnow writings (Box-folder 84: 11)
  - Corazon Aquino government (Box-folder 85: 1-4)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 85: 5-6)
  - U.S. relations, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  - Election, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - Indictment against Marcos (Box-folder 85: 9)
  - U.S. relations (Box-folder 86: 1-2)
  - Marcos (Box-folder 86: 3-4)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 86: 5-9)
  - Ninoy (Box-folder 87: 1-5)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 87: 6)
  - U.S. bases in the Philippines (Box-folder 87: 7-10)
  - Communists (Box-folder 88: 1)
  - Communist insurgency (Box-folder 88: 2-7)
  - Moslem insurgency (Box-folder 88: 8)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 88: 9)
  - Huks (Box-folder 88: 10-11)
  - Taruk (Box-folder 88: 12)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 88: 13)
  - U.S. bases in the Philippines (Box-folder 89: 1-2)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 89: 3-12)
  - Military intervention in PI (insurgency), 1985 (Box-folder 89: 13)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 90: 1-4)
  - Sugar (Box-folder 90: 5)
  - Javier assassination, 1986 (Box-folder 90: 6)
  - Interview, William Overholt, 1987 (Box-folder 90: 7)
  - 1 notebook, 1984 (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Economy, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 91: 2-3)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 91: 4-7)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - Licuanan letters (Box-folder 92: 2)
  - PNB scandal (Box-folder 92: 3)
  - Worcester, Dean (Box-folder 92: 4)
  - Quezon (Box-folder 92: 5)
  - MacArthur, Douglas (Box-folder 92: 6)
  - Pre WWII Philippines (Box-folder 92: 7-9)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 92: 10-12)
  - Catholic church (Box-folder 93: 1-2)
  - Interview, Glenn Gale (Box-folder 93: 3)
  - Aquino assassination (Box-folder 93: 4-6)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 93: 7-10)
  - Conein (Box-folder 93: 11)
  - Untitled (Box-folder 93: 12-13)
  - American bases (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 94: 2-10)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 95: 1-7)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 96: 1-9)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 97: 1-12)
  - Marcos (Box-folder 114: 1-6)
  - Martial law (Box-folder 114: 7-8)
  - Aquino, imprisonment trial in the United States (Box-folder 114: 9)
  - Elections (Box-folder 114: 10-12)
- Photographs, 1900s-1980s (Box 115)
  Approximately 100 8" x 10" research photographs of soldiers, politicians, and war.
- Electronic Files, 1999-2009 (Box 116)
  Two computer internal hard drives.